Thomas Krut



≜ Profile

Why limit yourself? That is often a valid question, in my experience. I come to the field of software engineering with a wealth of experience in other areas - technical maintenance, customer services, ESL teaching, to name a few. I believe every lesson I learned there will be an asset now. Add to the mix a fluency in code gained at the age of eleven, as well as a deep fascination with various software practices such as object oriented design patterns, TDD and version control. It did take a few years to get there, but I don't see how it could have happened any other way.



Education

Software engineering, Nackademin, Solna

Sep 2022—ongoing

Most courses here are geared towards Java backend technologies, but languages and frameworks to me are tools and not goals in and of themselves. I will learn anything that is needed in a project to get the job done. Personal goals throughout these studies have been to focus on readability and maintainability of code, understanding the advantages of and gaining experience in test driven development, as well as laying a solid foundation when it comes to collaborating with other developers on various projects.

English, University College of Borås

Aug 2002 - May 2003

English A (30 credits) and B (30 credits)



Work experience

Service technician, Selecta AB

Jan 2019—Aug 2022

Selecta is in the business of vending - supplying clients with a wide range of machines for coffee, sparkling water and snacks. I did technical field work entailing everything from repairs, installations, preventive maintenance, backend application administration, educating customers as well as communicating with suppliers on technical issues. Entering into the role I set one primary goal, namely to reduce response times and thereby increase customer satisfaction across my district. I reached this goal within two months, despite a steep learning curve mastering Selecta's proprietary vending equipment in combination with low staffing levels. In short, I managed to elevate quality of service in the face of some major challenges through hard work, a flexible mindset and an unwillingness to limit myself in terms of what could be accomplished.

Service agent, JOBmeal

Feb 2012-Jan 2019

JOBmeal is a major player in the vending sector, having recently consolidated all regional subsidiaries into a single nationwide organization. Keeping customers happy during this transitional period was certainly a challenge, as well as an opportunity to really make a difference. Apart from sales, every other aspect of the entire life cycle of a client's engagement with JOBmeal would typically require my attention. I would usually be the one to install and calibrate the equipment, deal with subsequent orders and service consultations, carry out repairs, educate client staff in charge of daily maintenance, perform hygienic checks, field fixes, software updates, hardware adjustments as well as removal of equipment in case of termination of contract. It certainly gave me an opportunity to set the standard for delivery of services, and I'm proud to say that most clients remained happily unaware of any turbulent circumstances on the corporate level.



Address Folkparksgatan 6D 511 53 Kinna Sweden

Mobile +4673 647 75 97

E-post thomas.krut@yh.nackademin.se



